hey guys I made this video a couple days
ago I really like the problem because it
had a cool shortcut but so many people
asked me to solve it without the
shortcut if you want to try this on your
own pause it right now cuz I'm going to
solve for x and y in 3 2 1 so first
let's copy both of these things down so
we have X Y = 36 and x^2 + y^2 = 78
let's start with this one first let's
divide both sides by X and it becomes y
= 36 /x so in the lower equation in the
place of the Y let's plug in
36x now this exponent goes to both the
top and the bottom so 36 /x^2 becomes
362 over x^2 and 362 is equal to
1296 and I don't really like fractions
so let's get rid of this x^2 in the
denominator we can do that by
multiplying both sides of the equation
by X2 and we're allowed to multiply both
sides by X squ because we know that X
cannot be zero if x were zero XY would
have to be zero so on the left hand side
this x^ squ will distribute to both of
these terms we have x^2 * x^2 which is X
4th and then we've got x^2 * this thing
the x^2 on top and the x^2 on bottom
will cancel each other out so the second
term is going to be 1296 and that's all
going to be equal to 78 x^2 next I want
to set this all equal to zero let's
subtract 78 x^2 from both sides on the
left hand side we end up with x 4 - 78
x^2 + 1296 and on the right hand side
these cancel each other out leaving us
with zero now we can solve this by
factoring this x 4 will break down into
x^2 and x^2 and then we want to find the
two numbers p and Q such that p + Q is
equal to -78 and P * Q is equal to
1296 this could take a little bit of
effort it ends up being -24 and -54 and
I did use a calculator to find these
next we have this * that equals 0 that
means that either this equals z or that
equals z so now we just got to solve
these two equations we can add 24 to
both sides of this equation or add 54 to
both sides of this equation on the left
hand side these cancel each other out
and we're left with X2 is equal to 24
and on this equation these two cancel
each other out so we're left with x^2 is
equal to 54 now both of these are in
terms of X squ so we're going to want to
square root both sides of both equations
for both of these square root of x squs
they're going to be absolute value of x
and to solve for the absolute values of
X each of these will become plus or
minus and now we have our four Val vales
of X posi < tk24 < tk24 posun 54 orun 54
and we know that Y is equal to 36 overx
so for each of these values of X we can
find the corresponding value of y in the
place of this x we'll plug in < TK 24
and the same thing for the rest of these
X's so now we have our answers for X and
Y let's check our work in the place of X
we can plug in < TK 24 and in the place
of Y we can plug in 36 over < tk24 this
exponent will go to the top and the
bottom 36 6 4 is equal to a huge number
and both of these < TK 24 to 4ths are
equal to 576 and then this huge number
divided by 576 is equal to 2916 and then
576 + 2916 is equal to 3492 and that is
the correct answer for X 4th + y 4th so
it checks out and in fact all of these
will check out so 3492 is the answer to
our question and this was the difficult
way to do it let's put a box around him
how exciting and I also got a lot of
request to see the haircut here it is I
got hat hair right now I don't know why
there's the haircut how exciting